# **Zheng (Thomas) Tang**

RESEARCH SCIENTIST - AMAZON ONE · EXPERT IN COMPUTER VISION AND MACHINE LEARNING

Amazon - Coral (SEA68), 2201 6th Ave, Seattle, WA 98121, USA

🛛 (+1) 206-669-5590 | 🔀 tangzhengthomas@gmail.com | 🏶 zhengthomastang.github.io | 🖸 zhengthomastang | 🛅 zhengthomastang

# Summary \_

Current Research Scientist - Amazon One at Amazon · Ph.D. in Electrical & Computer Engineering at the University of Washington (Advisor: Prof. Jenq-Neng Hwang) · 9-month internship at NVIDIA working on city-scale vehicle tracking and ReID with papers accepted to CVPR'19 and ICCV'19 · Leader of the winning team at the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18 · Organizing committee member of the 4th AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'20 · 2 finalist best student paper awards in ICPR'16

### Education

## **University of Washington (UW)**

Seattle, WA, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

- · Advised by Prof. Jeng-Neng Hwang (IEEE Fellow) at the Information Processing Lab
- Dissertation topic: Robust Video Object Tracking via Camera Self-Calibration

### **University of Washington (UW)**

Seattle, WA, USA

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

• GPA: 3.83/4.0

Sep. 2014 - Mar. 2016

### **Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT)**

Beijing, China

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

• GPA: 88.73/100

### Queen Mary University of London (QMUL)

London, UK

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

· First Class Honours

# Work Experience\_

Amazon Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH SCIENTIST - AMAZON ONE

Jul. 2019 - PRESENT

- Working on the research team for **Amazon One**, a fast and convenient identity service using people's palm for payment, entry and more
- · Advanced the development of a non-contact biometric identification system for palm signatures captured using light of varying polarity

NVIDIA Santa Clara, CA, USA

INTELLIGENT VIDEO ANALYTICS INTERN

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- · Created CityFlow, a city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera (MTMC) vehicle tracking and ReID, accepted at CVPR'19 (Oral)
- Proposed PAMTRI, a pose-aware multi-task network for vehicle ReID using highly randomized synthetic data, accepted at ICCV'19
- Joined the organizing committee of the 4th AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'20 that attracted 315 participating teams across 37 countries

### **University of Washington**

Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jun. 2015 - Jun. 2018

- Developed evolutionary camera calibration and clustering-based data association for vehicle tracking using fusion of visual and semantic features that achieved rank #1 in Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis) of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Designed multi-camera tracking based on fusion of adaptive appearance models, CNN features and license plate information that achieved rank #1 in Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID) of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Built a 3D human pose estimator to enable overlaying AR for medical simulation under 6-DoF camera motion, where a two-step evolutionary pose optimization for camera and humans (2EPOCH) is proposed (funded by ArchieMD Inc.)
- Proposed evolutionary camera self-calibration from tracking of humans to automatically back project 2D trajectories into 3D, which received
   2 Finalist Best Student Paper Awards in ICPR'16 (funded by Prism Skylabs)
- Invented an adaptive segmentation and tracking algorithm based on multi-kernel feedback that achieved top single-camera tracking accuracy (74.82%) on the NLPR\_MCT benchmark (funded by Madrona Venture Group)

# Teaching Experience \_\_\_\_

### **University of Washington**

Seattle, WA, USA

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

TEACHING ASSISTANT OF EE 508: STOCHASTIC PROCESSES IN ENGINEERING

• Designed topics for final projects, provided tutorials on hidden Markov model and held weekly office hours

# **Publications**

### JOURNAL ARTICLES

MOANA: An online learned adaptive appearance model for robust multiple object tracking in 3D

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 31934-31945. 2019

ESTHER: Joint camera self-calibration and automatic radial distortion correction from tracking of walking humans

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 10754-10766. 2019

Online-learning-based human tracking across non-overlapping cameras

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

TCSVT 28.10 (2018) pp. 2870-2883. 2018

### CONFERENCE PAPERS

PAMTRI: Pose-aware multi-task learning for vehicle re-identification using highly randomized synthetic data

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Stan Birchfield, Jonathan Tremblay, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang *Proc. ICCV*, pp. 211–220, 2019, Seoul, Korea

CityFlow: A city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera vehicle tracking and re-identification

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Ming-Yu Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Stan Birchfield, Shuo Wang, Ratnesh Kumar, David Anastasiu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR, pp. 8797-8806, 2019, Long Beach, CA, USA

Joint multi-view people tracking and pose estimation for 3D scene reconstruction

Zheng Tang, Renshu Gu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. ICME, pp. 1-6, 2018, San Diego, CA, USA

Single-camera and inter-camera vehicle tracking and 3D speed estimation based on fusion of visual and semantic features

Zheng Tang, Gaoang Wang, Hao Xiao, Aotian Zheng, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR Workshops, pp. 108-115, 2018, Salt Lake City, UT, USA

Inter-camera tracking based on fully unsupervised online learning

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICIP, pp. 2607-2611, 2017, Beijing, China

Multiple-kernel adaptive segmentation and tracking (MAST) for robust object tracking

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Jen-Hui Chuang

Proc. ICASSP, pp. 1115-1119, 2016, Shanghai, China

Camera self-calibration from tracking of moving persons

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Jen-Hui Chuang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICPR, pp. 260–265, 2016, Cancún, México

### Patents\_

Pose-aware multi-task learning for vehicle re-identification

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Stan Birchfield, Jonathan Tremblay, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang U.S. Patent No. 16/442,375, 2019

Robust human tracking with shadow removing and lighting changes

Jeng-Neng Hwang, Zheng Tang

UW CoMotion Record of Innovation No. 47423, 2015

# **Honors & Awards**

2019 <b>People's Choice Award</b> , Code for the Kingdom (C4TK) Hackathon	Seattle, WA, USA
2018 Winner of Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis). 2nd Al City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake City UT USA

2018 Winner of Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18

Salt Lake City, UT, USA

2017 **Winner of Track 2 (AI City Applications)**, 1st AI City Challenge Workshop in SmartWorld'17

San Francisco, CA, USA

2016 Finalist IBM Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16

Cancún, México

2016 Finalist Intel Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16

Cancún, México

### Skills

**Programming** C/C++ (expert), Python (expert), Java (proficient), MATLAB (expert), JavaScript (proficient), MEEX(expert)

Frameworks & Tools

PyTorch (expert), TensorFlow (expert), MXNet (proficient), Caffe (proficient), Git (expert), React (proficient)

**Languages** English (proficient), Mandarin (native), Cantonese (native), Spanish (elementary)